# ján <mark>čabala</mark>

Jasuschova 22, 040 23, Košice, Slovakia +421 911 116 302 cabala.jan@gmail.com https://github.com/zladovan/

#### **ABOUT**

I am a generalist who feels the best while swimming in uncharted waters.

During 10+ years as professional software developer I participated on a development of various types of applications and I tried multiple roles. I have experience with testing, programming web UI's, designing and implementing REST API's, building data analytics platform, configuring automated builds, deploying and monitoring of what I have built.

#### **PREFERENCES**

It depends on specific situation but generally I currenlty prefer to use:

**Language** Go for tooling

Kotlin for backends
Python for data analysis
TypeScript for Web UI's
Markdown for Documentation

VCS Git

**CI/CD** GitHub Actions + Shell scripts / Ansible

**DB** PostgreSQL as relational DB and as document storage too

**Monitoring** Prometheus + Grafana

Web UI Angular

**OS** Linux

**Others** GitHub for project hosting

Monorepository for multiple project organization Gradle as build tool not only for JVM projects

Docker + Docker compose for quick local setup / testing

gRPC for service-to-service communication

#### **PERSONAL**

## open-minded

I really do not like "black and white thinking", I usualy try to understand other ones perspectives, I have no problem to accept that I was not right, I realize that it can somtimes lead to hesitancy.

#### adaptable

I am enjoying most the time when there is a lot of new around, I am able to forget what I do not need now really fast.

## patient

I often hear it from others.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2019 – 2020 Software Engineer

#freelance E-commerce customer

implementation of aggregator and unified API for multiple sellers

complete solution from scratch

full stack development

Kotlin, PostgreSQL, gRPC, Angular, Gradle

**2019** Software Engineer / Co-Founder

#startup Unravela

https://unravela.com/organizations/twitter/

cofounding startup analyzing data mined from Git repositories implementation of reports and platform for generating reports

Python, Pandas, Go

2014 – 2019 Software engineer

#full\_time Wirecard s.r.o

mostly backend development on multiple projects

## Analytics system for credit card payments - OMNI

- > Data engineering
- > ETL implementation
- > Batch analyses implementation hourly, daily
- > Streaming aggregations implementation

Scala, ScalaTest, Cloudera's Hadoop distribution, Apache Spark, Apache Flink, Kafka, Avro, SBT, Gradle

## Analytics for loyalty system – CPOS

- > REST API implementation
- > ETL implementation
- > Batch analyses implementation daily

Java, JUnit, Play Framework, Oracle DB, MySQL, Elasticsearch, Pentaho, SBT, Gradle

## Alipay integration for POS terminals

> REST API implementation

Java, JUnit, Play Framework, Oracle DB, SBT

# Online payment gateway - Elastic Engine

- > adding supprort for new payment method
- > core maintanence
- > smaller core refactorings

Java, JUnit, Spring, Camel, MySQL, MyBatis, Maven

# **2013 – 2014** *Web developer*

#full\_time **Software a.g.** 

implementation of new features for ARIS Connect

Java, GWT, HTML, CSS

## 2012 – 2013 Automated test developer / Web developer

#full\_time Software a.g. (IDS Scheer SDC), Košice, Slovakia

implementation of GUI automated tests for ARIS Business Architect whole design and implementation of test results collecting system

- > results reporting API as a part of test framework
- > results queue consumer
- > results database
- > web application with results statistics, tables, graphs

Java, JUnit, TestNG, Abbot, Selenium, ActiveMQ, Spring MVC, JSP, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

# 2010 – 2012 Automated test developer

#part\_time IDS Scheer SDC, Košice, Slovakia

implementation of GUI automated tests for ARIS Business Architect

extending existing test framework

Java, JUnit, TestNG, Abbot, Selenium, Ant

### 2008 – 2009 Web developer

#part\_time AIT, s.r.o, Košice, Slovakia

analysis of user requirements

implementation of front end, back end and database layer

PHP, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

I am big fan of open source. I learned a lot from open source projects and I like to share my work too. Following are my most popular projects.

#### 2020 Gorched

https://github.com/zladovan/gorched

terminal based game inspired by Scorched earth my most popular project

Go, ASCII graphics

## 2019 Monorepo

https://github.com/zladovan/monorepo

showcase for building projects organized in monorepository with multiple popular CI tools

Shell script, Gradle, CircleCI, Bitbucket Pipelines, Travis CI, GitHub Actions

#### 2019 Gradle avrohugger plugin

https://github.com/zladovan/gradle-avrohugger-plugin gradle plugin for generating scala case classes from apache avro schemas, datafiles and protocols

Gradle, Groovy

To see others check out my GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/zladovan">https://github.com/zladovan</a>

## **EDUCATION**

## 2006 – 2010 Bachelor's degree

Technical University, Faculty of electrical engineering and information technology, Košice, Slovakia
Department of Computers and Informatics

# **2010 – 2012** Master's degree

Technical University, Faculty of electrical engineering and information technology, Košice, Slovakia
Department of Computers and Informatics

**Thesis:** Educational simulation system – Graphical editor implementation of editor for simulation system (inspired by Simulink) *Java*, *SWING* 

#### **HOBBY**

hiking, rock climbing, reading, programming